Guide to the Liberty Hyde Bailey papers, 1845-2004
Bailey, Liberty Hyde papers, 1845-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Liberty Hyde Bailey Papers, 1845 - 2004
21-2-3342
Liberty Hyde Bailey
43.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, negatives, audio recordings, newsclippings, published material, scrapbooks, memorabilia.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material relating to the life and work of Liberty Hyde Bailey.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Liberty Hyde Bailey was instrumental in separating Horticulture from Botany and establishing it as a distinct scientific pursuit. He was a botanist, horticulturalist, plant breeder, traveler and plant explorer, outstanding teacher, astute and successful administrator, lobbyist, rural sociologist, prolific writer and superb editor, environmentalist, philosopher, poet, and visionary.
Born on a farm in Michigan in 1858, Liberty Hyde Bailey graduated from the Michigan Agricultural College with a degree in botany. After working with the renowned botanist Asa Gray at Harvard, he returned to Michigan to teach horticulture and landscape gardening. In 1888, he came to Cornell to build a new curriculum in practical and experimental horticulture. In 1904, the Legislature passed a bill establishing the New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell, and Liberty Hyde Bailey became its first dean. In that role, he established new departments to complement existing fields of study, and appointed Cornell's first women professors. In 1908, Theodore Roosevelt appointed him to chair a presidential Country Life Commission.
Bailey retired from Cornell in 1913, but continued his scientific, practical, and philosophical pursuits, and made his home in Ithaca for the rest of his life. He wrote and edited numerous books, from textbooks to essays and poems. He traveled extensively on botanical collecting trips, and continued his studies of palms, blackberries, grapes, cabbages, pumpkins and squashes. During his lifetime, he received innumerable awards and honors. Liberty Hyde Bailey died in 1954 at the age of ninety-six.
CHRONOLOGY
March 15, 1858 Liberty Hyde Bailey, Jr. born near South Haven, Michigan
1862 Sarah Harrison Bailey, Liberty Hyde Bailey, Jr.'s mother, dies
1863 Liberty Hyde Bailey, Sr. marries Maria Bridges
1873 Liberty Hyde Bailey, Jr. delivers first public speech, "Birds," to the South Haven Pomological Society and is elected Ornithologist of the organization
1877-1882 Attends Michigan Agricultural College in Lansing, Michigan; studies Botany under the instruction of Dr. William Beal; meets Annette Smith
1882 Graduates from Michigan Agricultural College with a Bachelor of Science degree
1882 Works in Springfield, Illinois as a reporter for the Morning Monitor
Feb. 1883 Moves to Cambridge, Massachusetts to work as an assistant to Harvard botanist Asa Gray
June 1883 Marries Annette Smith
1885 Accepts professorship at Michigan Agricultural College; publishes first book "Talks Afield: About Plants and the Science of Plants"
1886 Receives Master of Science degree from Michigan Agricultural College
June 29, 1887 Daughter Sara May Bailey born
1887 Invited to give a series of lectures at Cornell
1889 Begins work as a Professor of Practical and Experimental Horticulture at Cornell
Nov. 17, 1889 Daughter Ethel Zoe Bailey born
1899 Appoints Anna Botsford Comstock as first female professor at Cornell
1904 Becomes Dean of New York State College of Agriculture at Cornell
1908 Leads a Commission on Country Life at the request of President Theodore Roosevelt
1911 Appoints Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose as Professors in Home Economics
1913 Retires from position of Dean; begins a Herbarium at home on Sage Place
1917-1949 Travels around the world on plant collecting expeditions
1926 Elected President of the Botanical Society of America
1935 Gives Hortorium to Cornell
1935 Daughter Sara dies
1938 Wife Annette dies
1944 Bailey's idea for a campus arboretum, botanical garden, and research field is realized with the opening of the Cornell Plantations
Mar. 15, 1948 Bailey misses 90th birthday party in Ithaca because he is on plant collecting trip in West Indies
Dec. 25, 1954 Bailey dies at his home in Ithaca
1958 United States Post Office issues a commemoration stamp honoring gardening and horticulture in America
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal, family, and professional papers relating to the life and work of Liberty Hyde Bailey and including correspondence, manuscripts, scrapbooks, journals, photographs, publications, genealogical and biographical information. Also records of the Bailey Hortorium. Correspondence and records of the Commission on Country Life. Also includes glass negatives of Bailiwick orchards and house construction; correspondence and agreements with Macmillan Company; photographs; Bailey's correspondence with his brother Marcus and daughter Ethel; and deeds, abstracts and title searches for the Bailey house on Sage Place; war ration books; agreement of gift of the Bailey Hortorium. Includes Bailey correspondence with Macmillan Company. Also, tape recordings (12 cassettes) and transcripts of an interview with Bailey by George H. M. Lawrence, 1951-1952, audio reels with interview by Edith Fox and Jackson Towne, 11/06/1951 and his typewriter and camera.
Includes a 1901 Junior Naturalist Club certificate signed by Bailey.
CD (MS Power Point) with posters prepared at Michigan State University using Cornell photographs, celebrating the 150th anniversary of the birth of Liberty Hyde Bailey, 2008. The posters were exhibited at the 2008 annual meetings of the American Society for Horticultural Science (July) and at the Great Lakes Expo (Michigan Horticultural Society and Michigan Vegetable Growers (December).
Printing block for the Loganberry illustration from "Gentes Herbarum," with page from the journal showing the illustration and a modern print; other various printing blocks, as well.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bailey, L. H.1858-1954.; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888.; Page, Walter Hines, 1855-1918.; Butterfield, Kenyon L. (Kenyon Leech), 1868-1935.; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946.; Bailey, Ethel Zoe.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Comstock, Anna Botsford, 1854-1930.; Bailey, Marcus.; Lawrence, George Hill Mathewson, 1910-1978; Liberty Hyde Bailey Hortorium.; New York State College of Agriculture.; Cornell University.; Cornell University. Junior Naturalist Club.; United States. Country Life Commission.; Macmillan Company.
Subjects:
Botany--Study and teaching.; Education, Rural.
Form and Genre Terms:
Audio cassettes.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
See also Liberty Hyde Bailey, New York State College of Agriculture and Agricultural Experiment Station Records, #21-2-84, Liberty Hyde Bailey Forestry Papers, #21-2-576 and College of Agriculture "Dean's Hat" items, #21-2-3144.
Liberty Hyde Bailey: A Man for All Seasons exhibition
Liberty Hyde Bailey Hortorium
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal, 1845 - 1955
Series II. Correspondence, 1879 - 1963
Series III. College of Agriculture, Cornell, and Education, 1891 - 1950
Series IV. Bailiwick, 1892 - 1934
Series V. Country Life Commission, 1905 - 1960
Series VI. Hortorium and Plant Collecting, 1887 - 1959
Series VII. Writings
Series VIII. Biographical Information, 1890-1990
Series IX. Photographs
Series X. Cyanotype albums and negatives
Series XI. Honors and Awards 1888-2004
Series XII. Miscellany 1887 - 1959
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal
  - Early family letters and miscellaneous papers. 1845-1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bailey Family material: News clippings, obituaries 1862 - 1838 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family Papers - Deeds and Mortgages 1863 - 1911 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Bailey House - Abstract of Title 1897 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Conveyance of Farm 1913 - 1915 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Early miscellaneous papers 1872-1891 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Scholiast" school newsletter by L.H. Bailey 1875 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annette Bailey's Autograph book 1875 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newsclipping scrapbook 1876 - 1887 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Notebook "Lists of Books and Botanical Apparatus - L.H. Bailey Jr., Botanic Gardens, Cambridge" 1883 (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Telegram offering Professorship at Michigan Agricultural College 1884 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Postcards, Menus, Columbian Exposition Pass, miscellaneous travel memorabilia 1888 - 1948 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Marcus B. Bailey Journal, sketches, poems 1899-1904 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Marcus B. Bailey Journal, sketches, poems 1895 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marcus B. Bailey Journal, sketches, poems: "Bailey's Joke Book" 1895 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Marcus B. Bailey Journal, sketches, poems 1896 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Marcus B. Bailey material 1897 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Marcus Benjamin Bailey - Bas Thimble Patent 1921 - 1928 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Marcus Benjamin Bailey - Death and Estate 1921 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Bailey and Harrison Families: Assorted correspondence and genealogical material 1905-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bailey Family genealogies and histories; newsclippings, photos 1928-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - South Haven - Estate - Correspondence and Accounts 1912 - 1915 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - South Haven - Estate - Correspondence and Accounts 1916 - 1919 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Annette (Mrs. L.H.) Bailey material 1904-1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annette Bailey's scrapbook 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellany belonging to Annette, Sara, and Ethel Zoe Bailey 1907 - 1935 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Items found in books owned by the Bailey family (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sara Bailey Sailor obituary Apr. 1936 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Annette Bailey - Estate 1946 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Bailey family correspondence 1910-1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bailey family correspondence 1911-1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bailey family correspondence 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bailey family correspondence 1907, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bailey family correspondence 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bailey family correspondence 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Kioshan, Chikungshan travel notes 1917 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Account Book of Mrs. L.H. Bailey" includes notes by Ethel Zoe 1901 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Receipts 1909 - 1912 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Receipts 1951 - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Checks 1911 - 1920 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Account Book and Receipts 1928 -1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Account Book and Receipts 1949 - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bank Statements 1948 - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Checkbooks July 1948 - July 1951 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Checkbooks July 1951 - June 1953 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Collection of poems (not by L.H.B.) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Collection of poems (not by L.H.B.) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Notes on Radio News for report to table at meal" c. 1947 - 1948 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Miscellany 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - General Correspondence, 1879 - 1958
    - Charles Fay Wheeler correspondence 1879-1881 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Charles Fay Wheeler correspondence 1879-1882 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Charles Fay Wheeler correspondence 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Charles Fay Wheeler correspondence 1882-1883 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Charles Fay Wheeler correspondence 1883-1890 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Charles Fay Wheeler correspondence; obituary 1883-1910 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence 1882-1886 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence 1886-1888 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence 1889-1893 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence 1894-1899 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence 1900-1904 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - L. H. Bailey Correspondence Copy Book, 1905-1909 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence 1905-1908 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence 1909 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence December 1909 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence January 1910 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence February 1910 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence March 1910-December 1910 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence 1911 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence 1912 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence 1913 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence 1914-1915 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence 1919-1924 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence 1926-1954 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Ernest Braunton Correspondence and Biography 1941 - 1943 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - David Fairchild 1929 - 1950 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence relating to Liberty Hyde Bailey: A - F 1953 - 1954 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence relating to Liberty Hyde Bailey: G - Z 1953 - 1954 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Photostats: Eustace, Aronovici, Cook, Britton, Killip 1888 - 1951 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Photostats: C.L. Shear 1890 - 1894 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - P.H. Rolfs 1923 - 1935 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - G.N. Lauman 1896 - 1920 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - A.F. Blakeslee 1925, 1944, 1950 - 1951 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Lewis Knudson Correspondence 1944 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Thomas W. Whitaker 1945 - 1958 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Photocopies of letters from Bailey 1940 - 1946 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Photocopies of letters from Bailey 1940 - 1946 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Anna B. Comstock, Ethel Z. Bailey, Travel, Personal 1929 - 1953 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Photocopies of 2 letters from Bailey to John Nolen 1922, 1923 (Box 46, Folder 32)
  - Macmillan and Publisher Correspondence, 1908 - 1963
    - Publisher correspondence 1889-1890 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Publisher correspondence, 1891-1899 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Publisher correspondence, 1902-1907 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Publisher correspondence, 1908-1910 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence 1908 - 1909 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jan. - Jun. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jul. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Aug. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Sept. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Oct. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Nov. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Dec. 1910 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jan. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Feb. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Mar. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Apr. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence May, 1911 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jun. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jul. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Aug. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Sept. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Oct. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Nov. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Dec. 1911 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence 1912 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence May 1-16, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence May 18-30, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jun. 1-14, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jun. 15-30, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jul. 1-9, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jul 10-31, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Aug. 1914 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Sept. 1914 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Oct. 1-14, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Oct. 15-31, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Nov. 1-14, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Nov. 16-30, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Dec. 1-14, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Dec. 15-31, 1914 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jan. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jan. 15-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Feb. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Feb. 15-27, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Mar. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Mar. 15-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Apr. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Apr. 15-30, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence May 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence May 14-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jun. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jun. 51-30, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jul. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jul. 1-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Aug. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Aug. 15-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Sept. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Sept. 15-30, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Oct. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Oct. 15-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Nov. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Nov. 15-30, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 57)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Dec. 1-14, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 58)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Dec. 15-31, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 59)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jan. 1-14, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jan. 15-31, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Feb. 1-15, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 62)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Feb. 16-29, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 63)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Mar. 1-15, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 64)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Mar. 15-31, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 65)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Apr. 1-14, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 66)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Apr. 15-30, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 67)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence May, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 68)
    - Macmillan/Publisher Correspondence Jun. 1916 (Box 29, Folder 69)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1916 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1-14, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 15-31, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1-14, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 15-30, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 2-19, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 20-30, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 1-14, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 15-30, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Dec. 1-14, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Dec. 15-31, 1916 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. 2-13, 1917 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan.15-24, 1917 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. 25-31, 1917 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Feb. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Mar. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Apr. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Macmillan Correspondence May, 1917 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Dec. 1917 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Feb. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Mar. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Apr. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Macmillan Correspondence May, 1918 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jun. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Dec. 1918 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Feb. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Mar. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Apr. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Macmillan Correspondence May, 1919 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jun. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Dec. 1919 (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 49)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Feb. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 50)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Mar. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 51)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Apr. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 52)
    - Macmillan Correspondence May, 1920 (Box 30, Folder 53)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jun. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 54)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 55)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 56)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 57)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 58)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 1920 (Box 30, Folder 59)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. - Mar. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Apr. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Macmillan Correspondence May, 1921 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jun. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Oct. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Nov. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Dec. 1921 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jan. 1922 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Feb. 1922 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Apr. 1922 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Macmillan Correspondence May, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jun. 1922 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 1-14, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Jul. 15-31, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 1-14, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Aug. 15-31, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Macmillan Correspondence Sept. 1-14, 1922 (Box 31, Folder 20)